homedecorators.com 2019-12-31

# The Home Depot, Inc. Privacy and Security Statement

The Home Depot values and respects the privacy of its customers and visitors. In the course of operating our business and interacting with you, we collect, use, and share personal information. We do so to process and fulfill your orders, to improve our in-store and digital offerings, to create consistent in-store and digital experiences for you, to protect the rights and information of our customers and our company, and for the other purposes disclosed in this Privacy and Security Statement. 

This Privacy and Security Statement provides you with information about how we collect, use, and share personal information, and describes choices and rights available regarding your personal information. If you have any questions, please contact us via the channels listed below. 

This Privacy and Security Statement describes the privacy practices of The Home Depot, Inc. and its subsidiaries, divisions, affiliates, brands, and other The Home Depot companies that link to this Privacy and Security Statement, including The Home Depot Foundation (subject to exceptions noted in The Home Depot Foundation section below) (collectively, "The Home Depot," "our," “us,” or "we"). It applies to the information we collect in association with your interactions with us, including, but not limited to:

  * Use of our websites, including mobile websites
  * Visits to our stores or attendance at our events
  * Use of our applications for mobile phones, tablets, or other smart devices
  * Phone and email communications with us
  * Social media interactions on our websites and other third party websites like Facebook, YouTube, Pinterest, Google+, Instagram, and Twitter
  * Viewing our online advertisements or emails
  * Interactions with our authorized service providers

It also applies to personal information that we receive from business partners and other third parties. You can find out more information about our collection of personal information below.

If you are applying for a job with us, please see the end of this Privacy and Security Statement regarding our practices with respect to the information we collect in association with your application.  The remainder of this Privacy and Security Statement does not apply to applicant information.  

This Privacy and Security Statement does not apply to the practices of The Home Depot Canada or The Home Depot Mexico. The privacy policy for Canada can be found at [homedepot.ca/privacy](https://www.homedepot.ca/en/home/customer-support/privacy-and-security.html). The privacy policy for Mexico can be found at [homedepot.com.mx/privacy](http://homedepot.com.mx/aviso-privacidad). Also, this policy does not apply to third-party websites accessible through our websites. Other The Home Depot companies may provide different privacy and security statements or policies for their business operations that may differ from this Privacy and Security Statement. For example, this Privacy and Security Statement does not apply to [blinds.com](http://www.blinds.com/), [justblinds.com](http://www.justblinds.com/), [americanblinds.com](http://www.americanblinds.com/), or [thecompanystore.com](http://www.thecompanystore.com/).  You can find the applicable description of privacy practices by clicking on the links available on the web sites operated by the other The Home Depot companies, or by looking in the menus of their mobile applications.  

As noted above, we collect personal information when you visit our stores, when you contact us, when you interact with or use our digital offerings, and from business partners and other third parties. 

The table below describes the categories of personal information we collect, the sources we collect the information from, our purposes for collecting the information, and the types of recipients that may receive the information from us. And you can find more details in the “What Do We Collect?,” “How Do We Collect Information?,” and “Information Sharing” sections that follow. 

Directly from you or the devices you use to access digital services, such as websites, mobile applications, and applications for connected devices.

Other customers that may provide us with your information to recommend a product or service, ship products to you, or list you as a recipient of products or services.

Companies that provide services on our behalf (e.g., installers).

Security and fraud prevention services that help us confirm that transactions are valid and otherwise help us protect our assets and you. 

Marketing companies that help us learn about our customers and the devices they use to access digital content.

Companies that supplement our customer records with additional information.

Shipping providers that update address information.

Social media platforms.

Advertising companies and content publishers that present you with our ads. 

Payment and transaction processors.

Communications and mailing vendors.

The signals emitted by your mobile devices when you travel through our stores. 

Service providers that process information on our behalf, such as shipping vendors, providers of digital analytics services, and fraud prevention.

Manufacturers of products and providers of extended warranty services.

Joint marketing partners.

Financial services companies, such as for home improvement loans, processing payments, and for managing The Home Depot credit card accounts.

Any successor to all or part of our business.

Advisors and consultants.

Advertising partners.

Law enforcement, public and government authorities, and other entities as we deem reasonably necessary to comply with law, support investigations, and protect the rights and property of you, us, and others.  

Our affiliates and subsidiaries.

Service providers that process information on our behalf, such as shipping vendors, providers of digital analytics services, and fraud prevention services.

Manufacturers of products and providers of extended warranty services.

Financial services companies, such as for home improvement loans, processing payments, and for managing The Home Depot credit card accounts.

Joint marketing partners.

Any successor to all or part of our business.

Advisors and consultants.

Advertising partners.

Law enforcement, public and government authorities, and other entities as we deem reasonably necessary to comply with law, support investigations, and protect the rights and property of you, us, and others.  

Our affiliates and subsidiaries.

Service providers that process information on our behalf, such as shipping vendors, providers of digital analytics services, and fraud prevention services.

Manufacturers of products and providers of extended warranty services.

Joint marketing partners.

Financial services companies, such as for home improvement loans, processing payments, and for managing The Home Depot credit card accounts.

Any successor to all or part of our business.

Advisors and consultants.

Advertising partners.

Law enforcement, public and government authorities, and other entities as we deem reasonably necessary to comply with law, support investigations, and protect the rights and property of you, us, and others.  

Our affiliates and subsidiaries.

We collect information directly from you. 

For example, we collect information when you:

  * Visit our stores or other facilities
  * Register for an account or complete a survey 
  * Make an online or in-store purchase
  * Use an online forum, submit a question or answer to our Product Q & A, provide us with comments or reviews, or contact our call centers
  * Upload or share a photo, submit a request, submit information, or post other digital content through one of our websites, applications or via social media interactions on third party websites like Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest or Twitter
  * Register for one of our programs or offers, or apply for a The Home Depot credit card or a home improvement loan
  * Participate in a sweepstakes, contest, promotion, program, clinic, or workshop
  * Rent equipment or vehicles or request a quote, warranty, or other information
  * Return a product or use a rebate
  * Request we send you an electronic copy of your in-store receipt
  * Apply or inquire about employment
  * Submit information via our websites, mobile websites, or applications

We collect information from you passively. 

We use tools like browser cookies, flash cookies, pixel tags, and web beacons to collect information when you use our websites and applications or interact with our emails. For more information about these tools and the choices you may have, please read the Our Tracking Tools section.  And we use cameras and other technologies in our stores, in parking lots and at other facilities to learn about customer traffic and for fraud prevention, security, and asset protection 

We collect information from Affiliates of The Home Depot. 

We may receive information about you from companies that are controlled by or under common control with The Home Depot (our “Affiliates”). 

We collect information from third parties. 

  * In the course of serving you and operating our business, we collect information from a variety of third parties. For example, we collect information from:
  * Shipping companies
  * Installers
  * Subscription providers
  * Your friends and contacts
  * Marketing companies that help us learn about consumer interests and trends
  * Companies that supplement our customer records with additional information
  * Online advertising and analytics providers
  * Social media platforms
  * Mailing vendors
  * Public records resources
  * Suppliers of property information
  * Companies that help us process payments
  * Service providers that operate on our behalf and collect information
  * Financial institutions and other companies that help provide or support financial products and offers
  * Security and fraud prevention providers
  * Manufacturers and other businesses with which we conduct joint offers or programs

Here are some examples of how we use the information we collect: 

To respond to you and provide you with goods and services you request. 

  * Fulfilling orders, ensuring proper delivery, or providing services (such as delivering an electronic copy of your receipt)
  * Administering your participation in a contest, sweepstakes, or other promotion or sending you prizes you might have won
  * Registering you for a particular website, loyalty program, or extended warranty service, or providing you with information regarding such programs or services
  * Processing a return (to learn more about our Returns Policy, click here)
  * Responding to a product or service review

To improve our business, products, and services.

  * Improving our websites, mobile applications, and applications for other connected devices
  * Identifying ways to make our products and services better
  * Improving store layouts
  * Developing new ways to purchase and browse our products and services
  * Personalizing the content on our digital services (e.g., websites, mobile applications, and connected device applications) so you have a consistent experience

To identify and assess website and device application trends and customer interests.

  * Recommending products and services that may interest you
  * Identifying the devices you use to interact with us so that we can provide you with a consistent experience
  * Identifying your interests based on your interactions with us and information we have received from third parties or publicly available sources
  * Updating our product inventories to meet projected demand

For security and asset protection purposes.

  * In-store, parking lot, and facility cameras track store traffic and stock  
  * Mitigating credit losses
  * Confirming the identity of our customers who rent trucks or certain types of tools or equipment
  * Retrieving unreturned tools or other equipment
  * Processing and tracking returns
  * Detecting and preventing fraud and malicious activities on our digital offerings and in your accounts

For our marketing.

  * Sending you communications about special The Home Depot promotions or offers via regular mail, email, phone, or other electronic channels, including ads on social media platforms
  * Sending you newsletters and other information you have requested
  * Informing you of new in-store or digital products and service offerings
  * Passing along information about offers from our Affiliates and other companies we think you might find interesting

You can update certain marketing communications preferences by following the instructions in the Manage Marketing Preferences section below. 

To provide you with ads and other communications that align with your interests, we may use information collected across different online services and collected from the various devices you use. For example, if you view a product on our website or mobile application, we may arrange for you to see ads for that product or similar products on our or third party websites and applications.

To communicate with you about your account or our relationship. 

  * Notifying you about changes to this Privacy and Security Statement, the Terms of Use of our websites or device applications, or changes to any of our programs in which you might be enrolled
  * Updating you regarding shipping, product availability, product recalls, warranty information, or rebates
  * Sending you other transactional or relationship communications 

For employment purposes. 

  * Processing and responding to your application for or inquiry regarding employment with us.

For social media engagement.

  * When you engage with our content on or through social networking websites, plug-ins and applications, you may allow us to have access to certain social media account information (e.g., name, username, email address, gender) as determined by the settings of the social media platforms to deliver the content or as part of the operation of the website, plug-in or application
  * Such social media platforms may collect information about your use of our services and may notify other users of the platform about your activities on our websites and device applications 
  * These social media platforms may also use cookies or other technologies to provide services or track your online activities over time and across multiple websites and device applications. Your interactions with social media features are governed by the respective privacy policies of the social media platforms

For other uses we may disclose to you.

  * We may also use information for purposes disclosed to you at the point of collection, as authorized by you, or as otherwise permitted or required by law.

We may share your information for our business purposes and as legally required or permitted by law. Please see below for examples of circumstances in which we share information.

With third parties who perform services on our behalf. 

  * Service providers, such as our delivery service providers who ship and deliver your orders
  * Providers of security and payment services
  * Shipping and mailing vendors
  * Providers of digital analytics services
  * Third parties that help us communicate with you
  * Marketing and advertising companies that help us learn about our customers or deliver advertisements
  * We might also share information with the vendors and manufacturers of our products and services to respond to your reviews and questions

In association with financial products.

  * We work with third parties to offer financial products, such as The Home Depot credit card and home improvement loans
  * We share information with these third parties so that they can provide you with tailored information about products and services and special offers
  * These third parties also have their own privacy statements that set out the manner in which they will collect, use and disclose personal information
  * We encourage you to review each third party’s privacy statement at the time you submit your application for such financial products

To provide extended warranty services.

  * If you purchase a The Home Depot Extended Warranty Service you will be required to provide information such as your name and address to our warranty service providers 
  * We limit by contract the ways they may use your information to provide The Home Depot Extended Warranty Services
  * We encourage you to review each service provider's privacy statement at the time you submit your personal information for such services

With any successor to all or part of our business. 

  * For example, if all or part of our business is sold or otherwise acquired, we may sell or disclose our customer lists and other personal information we collect in preparation for or as part of that transaction

If we think we have to in order to comply with the law.

  * For example, we will disclose information to respond to a court order or subpoena. We may also disclose information if a government agency or investigatory body requests it

With our business partners.

  * For example, we might share information with one of our Affiliates or a business partner who is running a joint promotion with us or who provides a product or service in partnership with us
  * And we may share information with joint marketing partners

With advertising and marketing partners.

  * To manage and deliver advertising, including by placing ads on the websites and applications you access
  * To measure the effectiveness of our advertising campaigns
  * To identify the ads you have already seen, so that you don’t have to see the same ads too many times
  * To better understand your preferences and interests 

For security and fraud prevention.

  * We will disclose information to detect, prevent, and investigate fraud or unlawful activities
  * We may also disclose information to collect debts or recover unreturned rental items

At your direction.

  * For example, if you ask us to provide your information to a third-party to facilitate the delivery of services or resolution of a dispute

We disclose the following categories of personal information for our business purposes, such as to third parties who perform services on our behalf:

  * Identifiers
  * Demographics
  * Commercial information
  * Biometric information to third parties providing services on our behalf 
  * Information about web and application activities and interactions with connected devices
  * Location information
  * In-store, parking lot, and facility video recordings and recordings of customer care conversations
  * Professional information
  * Inferences regarding your preferences, interests, and other characteristics 

We do not share your information with third parties in exchange for money. We do share certain personal information in exchange for insights and other valuable services. California law treats such sharing as a “sale” even if no money is exchanged. These disclosures involve:

  * Identifiers
  * Demographics
  * Commercial information
  * Information about web and application activities and interactions with connected devices 
  * Location information
  * Professional information
  * Inferences regarding your preferences, interests, and other characteristics

You can register or change your preferences to receive or not receive marketing communications from us by clicking [here](https://www.homedepot.com/c/Manage_Marketing_Preferences). Please allow sufficient time for your preferences to be processed. Even if you opt out of receiving marketing messages, we may still contact you for transactional purposes like confirming or following up on an order or service request, responding to customer service inquiries, asking you to review a product or service you have ordered, or notifying you of product recalls or rebates. And you may continue to see general audience marketing, such as The Home Depot ads on other websites that are placed based on the content available on the sites.  If you later opt back into getting marketing communications from us, we will remove your information from our opt-out databases. 

Registered website users can update their information at the My Account section of our website. If you are not a registered website user, refer to the Contact Us section below for information about how you can contact us.

Our websites and device applications are not created for children. To our knowledge we neither collect online information from nor sell information regarding children under 18. If you are a parent or guardian and think we have information about your child, please email [customercare@homedepot.com](mailto:customercare@homedepot.com). To learn more about how to protect your child online, visit the FTC's [www.OnGuardOnline.gov](http://www.onguardonline.gov/). You may also want to read the helpful information about children and privacy that the FTC provides by clicking [here](http://www.onguardonline.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).

If you live in California and have an established business relationship with us, you can request a list of the personal information we have shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. We will also give you a list of the third parties that have received your information. You can make a request one time each year, by emailing or writing to us at the address below. Please mention in your letter that you are making a "California Shine the Light" inquiry. We will respond within 30 days.

The California Consumer Privacy Act (“CCPA”) provides California residents with the following privacy rights:

  * Right to Know:  Consumers have a right to request information about the personal information that we collect, use, disclose, and sell. 
  * Right to Delete: Consumers have a right to request the deletion of personal information that we have collected from them, though we may be permitted to retain personal information for certain purposes.
  * Right to Opt-out of Sales: We do not share your information with third parties in exchange for money.  We do share your information with third parties to enhance your experiences with us, to improve our ability to serve you, and to keep you aware of our products, services, and offers.  California law may treat some such disclosures as sales, and consumers have a right to direct us not to sell their personal information.
  * Right to Opt-out of Financial Incentive Programs that we may offer.
  * Non-Discrimination: We may not discriminate against you for exercising your rights under the CCPA. We may, however, provide a different level of service or charge a different rate if the difference is reasonably related to the value of your information. 

If you are a California resident, or an authorized agent acting on behalf of a California resident, and would like to exercise one of these rights, please visit our website [here](https://www.homedepot.com/c/Exercise_My_Privacy_Rights) or call us at [1-800-394-1326.](tel:+1-800-394-1326) For help submitting a request in one of our stores, please visit the customer service desk. Please note that we may require additional information from you in order to honor your request, and there may be circumstances where we will not honor your request, as permitted under the CCPA. For example, if you request deletion, we may need to retain certain personal information to comply with our legal obligations. 

If you would like to exercise your right to opt out of the sale of your personal information, please click here: [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.homedepot.com/c/Exercise_My_Privacy_Rights). 

Some of the tracking tools used on our websites, mobile applications, and other digital services may involve the sharing of personal information with third parties in exchange for their support in enhancing your experiences with us, improving our ability to serve you, or keeping you aware of our products, services, and offers.  To exercise your choices regarding those tools, please read the Our Tracking Tools section below, particularly the section on controlling our tracking tools.

When you place orders on our websites or through our mobile applications, all of your order information, including your credit card number and delivery address, is transmitted through the Internet using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) technology. SSL technology causes your browser to encrypt your order information before transmitting it to our secure server. SSL technology, an industry standard, is designed to prevent someone other than operators of our websites from capturing and viewing your personal information.

While we use industry standard means to protect our websites and your information, the Internet is not 100% secure. The measures we use are appropriate for the type of information we collect. We cannot promise that your use of our websites or mobile applications will be completely safe. We encourage you to use caution when using the Internet. Online access to your personal information is protected with a password you select. We strongly recommend that you do not share your password and that you use unique passwords for all of your online accounts.

Our websites contain links to third party websites. If you click on one of those links, you will be taken to websites we do not control. This Privacy and Security Statement does not apply to the information practices of those websites. You should read the privacy policies of other websites carefully. We are not responsible for third party websites.

If you have additional questions, concerns, would like information about how customers with disabilities may access this Privacy and Security Statement in an alternative format, or would like to exercise your rights, you can call us at [1-800-466-3337](tel:+1-800-466-3337), fax us at [1-877-959-9768](tel:+1-877-959-9768), or reach us by email at [CustomerCare@homedepot.com](mailto:Customer_Care@homedepot.com). You can write to us at: 

The Home Depot 

Attention: Privacy Official Customer Care 

2455 Paces Ferry Road Atlanta, GA 30339-4024

Changes to this Privacy and Security Statement

Effective Date: January 1, 2004

Last Revision Date: December 30, 2019

From time to time we may change our privacy policies. We will notify you of any material changes to our Privacy and Security Statement by posting an updated copy on our website. Please check our website periodically for updates.

Tracking Tools We Use

We collect personal and other information using digital tracking tools, such as cookies and web beacons, when you use our websites or mobile applications, interact with our emails or applications provided on connected devices, or otherwise engage with our digital offerings. We also partner with third parties that collect information this way. These third parties may place similar tracking tools on our websites, applications, and advertising to facilitate tracking, advertising, and measurement services. 

The tools may collect information about your activities over time and on various digital services offered by us or others. 

The tools that we, our vendors, and third parties use include:

  * Browser and flash cookies. Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer or other connected device to identify your browser or to store information or settings. Your browser may provide the ability to be notified when you receive certain types of cookies and how to restrict or disable certain cookies. Flash cookies generally can be disabled only by accessing Adobe Flash settings (information available here)
  * Server logs, which record information about the device, browser, operating system, network, and other resources you use to access our digital services
  * Web beacons and pixels. These are small electronic images deployed on websites and emails that collect information about how users interact with content
  * Application software. Software in our mobile and other connected-device applications collects information about how you interact with the digital services 

We, our service providers, and third parties use the information collected via these tools to:  

  * Identify new visitors and users
  * Recognize returning customers
  * Learn how you came to access our digital services
  * Keep you logged into our digital services
  * Personalize your experience on our website, device applications, and third-party social networking websites, plug-ins and applications
  * Identify your location as determined by the IP address of your devices
  * Optimize and tailor our websites and device applications
  * Make product recommendations and provide you with advertising content in which we think you will be interested. As part of this customization, we may observe your behaviors on our device applications, our websites, or on other websites and applications. We may also get information about your browsing history and online activities from our trusted business partners and vendors
  * Better understand our audience, our customers, our website visitors and device application users, and their respective interests, including by learning about your online activities across devices
  * Provide correct pricing and ads for the local store you select

Online Interest-Based Ads

We work with digital advertising and marketing companies to provide you with ads that meet your interests and that enhance your experience with us. These ads may be displayed on websites or device applications operated by us or third parties, and they may be based on information about your activities or preferences collected by us or third parties. For example, if you visit another website and provide your ZIP code, you may see advertising for products available at The Home Depot Store near you on another website. We work with third parties to monitor and optimize ad delivery so that you don’t receive the same ad too many times and to determine whether you were interested in the ads. As noted above, these third parties collect information with their own cookies, pixels, and related tracking technology. 

To learn more about interest-based ads and to opt out of certain types of interest-based advertising and certain other uses of information collected over time and across different online services and devices, click here. Some of the social media platforms we work with may serve you with interest-based advertising on their platforms. In addition to or instead of the opt-out mechanism linked above, you may be able to opt out of their interest-based advertising by changing your advertising preferences in the platforms after you log in.

Controlling Our Tracking Tools

This section provides you with information about the options available to you to control our tracking tools.  Some of our tracking tools share information with third parties in exchange for their support in enhancing your experiences with us, improving our ability to serve you, or keeping you aware of our products, services, and offers.  Such disclosures may be considered sales under certain laws even though we do not sell your personal information to third parties for money.  The options below will help you opt-out of such sales, and you should visit [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://www.homedepot.com/c/Exercise_My_Privacy_Rights) for additional options and information.

Disable browser cookies: Your browser may give you the ability to control cookies, some of which may enable third parties to collect data about your use of our websites.  You can adjust your browser settings to block all cookies. Certain browsers also allow you to limit the blocking of cookies to specific websites. Instructions for blocking cookies on commonly used browsers can be found at the links below. You will need to adjust the settings on each browser and on each device for which you wish to block cookies. Please note that disabling cookies may limit the functionality of our websites.

  * [Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en): [Instructions for blocking cookies from a specific website](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647)
  * [Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences): [Instructions for blocking cookies from a specific website](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/block-websites-storing-cookies-site-data-firefox)

Disable Flash cookies: Third parties may collect data about your usage of our websites via Flash cookies. To disable Flash cookies, follow these [instructions](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/). This setting will need to be adjusted on each device for which you wish to block Flash cookies. 

Exercise interest-based advertising opt-outs: Certain coalitions of advertisers allow consumers to opt-out of receiving interest-based advertising from members of the coalitions. Please follow the links below to opt-out of receiving interest-based advertising from members of these coalitions. You will need to exercise these opt-outs on each browser on each device for which you wish to opt-out of interest-based advertising.

Limit mobile device interest-based advertising: You can adjust your advertising preferences on mobile devices through your device settings:

  * iOS Devices: Go to Settings > Privacy > Advertising (at the bottom of the screen) > Turn on Limit Ad Tracking
  * Android Devices: Go to Google Settings > Ads > Opt Out of Interest-Based Ads

When you opt out of receiving targeted advertising, you may still see general audience advertising regarding our products and services. We may deliver advertising to a general audience or place advertising on websites and other platforms that relate to our advertisements. For example, if you opt out of targeted advertising and visit a do-it-yourself website, you may see advertising on the website that promotes products and services related to the content. 

We may update this section from time to time with information about new tools that may be available to you to register your preferences.   

Your Choices Regarding Location Information

If you use our mobile websites, mobile applications, or other smart device applications we may collect location data obtained from your device. If you use our websites, we may collect location data obtained from your IP address. We use this location data to find our nearest store to you, provide product pricing and availability at our stores near you, provide you with coupons and other offers based on your location, and provide driving directions to our stores. Certain of our device applications may also use this information to determine if you are shopping in one of our stores. If you are, we present you information relevant to in-store customers. For many devices, you can disable our collection of location information in the settings menu of your device or via device portals. 

Our "Do Not Track" policy: Some browsers have a "Do Not Track" feature that lets you tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. These browser features are not uniform. So, we are not currently set up to respond to those signals.

My Account registration is an optional service provided by our website. You do not have to register to browse or shop online. When you register, you are asked for personal information such as your name, address, phone number, email address, and a username and password that you select. You may also optionally provide information regarding your interests and home improvement projects or register your credit cards. This information may be used to help make your online shopping quicker and easier, by pre-filling certain parts of your shopping information. 

Click [here ](https://www.homedepot.com/c/PH_MyAccount)to read more about the terms and conditions that govern your registration and use of our My Account service.

As noted above, this Privacy and Security Statement applies to interactions between The Home Depot Foundation (“Foundation”) and the Foundation’s donors, volunteers, grantees, and website visitors. The Foundation may collect information about you when you visit the Foundation website, apply for a grant, register for a fundraising event, volunteer for a charitable project or make a donation to the Foundation. The Foundation uses this information to process your request, learn about how people use and interact with the Foundation’s website, improve its services and communicate with you about the Foundation, grants, or Foundation-related events. Except as described in this section, the Foundation will not sell, share, or trade your name or other information that reasonably identifies you with any other party. The Foundation may share such information with trusted third parties (e.g., The Home Depot and service providers) that assist the Foundation in operating its website, reviewing grants, conducting its fundraising events or operating its charitable business. The Foundation permits these third parties to use the information only in support of and as directed by the Foundation. The Foundation may also share such information with a legal successor to the Foundation and with other third parties if we believe we have to in order to comply with law and legal process. The Foundation will not send donor mailings on behalf of other organizations.

Click [here](https://corporate.homedepot.com/community) to read more about the Foundation and its support of our communities.

This section describes how we collect and share information in connection with your application for employment.  The above sections of this Privacy and Security Statement do not apply to our processing of applicant information.  

We collect the following categories of personal information in association with your application for employment with us:  

Identifiers: such as your name, email address, phone numbers, username, online identifier, device identifier, IP address, social media handle, physical address, and government-issued identifiers.

Demographics: such as your date and place of birth; age; gender; nationality; native language; family and marital status; veteran status; details of family members and dependents (name, date of birth, relationship to applicant or candidate); and emergency contact name, address and telephone number.

Information regarding eligibility to work: such as passport or visa information.

Financial information:  certain financial or banking information.

Work history: such as position/title; location; work address; start and end-dates of employment; contact information for former employer(s) or other persons or entities for which work was performed; business unit; function; organizational unit; dates and reasons for hire, promotion, transfer, status change and termination; employment status (full-time or part-time); employment type; job performance and related evaluative information; information relating to awards, certifications, and professional associations and volunteer activities; language proficiency; skills.

Education information:  such as education level, training, development, professional degrees, and certificates. 

Inferences and other characteristics:  such as any observations we may make based on your application or interview, and information provided by your references. We use the information we collect for the following purposes:

  * Processing your application
  * Evaluating your qualifications
  * Administering and managing our recruitment processes
  * Managing payroll and compensation
  * Developing financial and employment metrics
  * Budgeting, forecasting, and reporting
  * Monitoring and complying with legal requirements
  * Responding to internal or external audits and inquiries, law enforcement requests, or requests from administrative or judicial authorities
  * Monitoring and promoting compliance with our policies and procedures 
  * Security

If you provide us with personal information about members of your family and/or other dependents (e.g., for emergency contact), it is your responsibility to provide them with the information contained in this section.
